Prisoner 3-2034.
(近藤)囚人番号３ ２０３４｡
田中古兵衛｡ 幕府の役人35人を
殺害した凶悪な殺人鬼｡
Kohei Tanaka.
A vicious serial killer who murdered
35 Bakufu employees.
人斬り古兵衛と呼ばれる
過激攘夷派 暁党の幹部｡
Also known as Kohei the Manslayer, a leader in the
Akatsuki faction of the radical Anti-Foreigner Faction.
幕吏四十数人に包囲され➡
Surrounded by over forty Bakufu officials,
with a dozen cuts on his body,
全身十数か所の
刀傷を受けながらも➡
顔色ひとつ変えずに応戦し
幕吏７人を殺害｡
he didn't bat an eye as
he killed seven officials.
捕縛後も
一切の尋問拷問にも動じず➡
After being captured, he has
yet to respond to torture,
ひと言も発さず
口を閉ざしたままでいる｡
and we haven't been able to
get him to open his mouth.
(近藤)
いや この言い方は語弊があった｡
No, that would be the
wrong way to put it.
正確に言えば 口は開いている｡
と いうか開きっぱなしだ｡
His mouth is definitely open.
In fact, it's been open the whole time.
ﾔﾂは どんな拷問のなかにあっても
笑顔を絶やさない｡
He never stops smiling, regardless
of the torture he's going through.
ああして楽しそうに
いつも笑っているんだ｡
He's always smiling like
he's enjoying it all.
["It All Depends On How You Use
The 'Carrot and Stick' Method"]
(土方)また 上も
面倒なﾔﾂよこしたもんだな｡
The suits have given us
a real pain to deal with.
(近藤)近く 暁党が江戸で
大規模なﾃﾛ活動を➡
There have been reports of a large-scale terrorist
attack in the works by the Akatsuki faction.
画策しているとの
情報が入っている｡
間違いなくﾔﾂは
詳しい情報を握っている｡
He must know the details.
(土方)
それを ｵﾚたちに吐かせろと？
And we're supposed to
force it out of him?
まぁ そういうことだ｡
やれるかね？
Yeah, pretty much.
Can you do it?
(沖田)少なくとも 拷問で
口を割らせるのはﾑﾘでしょう｡
I doubt we'll be able to make
him talk through torture.
見てくだせぇ あのドＭﾂﾞﾗ｡
Look at that masochistic face.
あれが敵にとっつかまって
絶体絶命のﾔﾂの➡
Does he look like someone in a desperate situation
after being captured by the enemy?
ﾂﾗに見えますかい？
He isn't thinking about how
to get out of this situation.
ﾔﾂは この場から抜げ出すことなど
考えちゃいない｡
楽しんでるんでさぁ｡ この状況を｡
He's enjoying the situation.
(山崎)おそらくあれは
拷問の訓練を受けていますね｡
He must have been trained
to take torture.
ﾔﾂにとって
痛みは拒むものじゃない｡
He doesn't reject pain.
受容し 賛美される代物なんです｡
He's probably learned
to seek and relish it.
例え 手足をちぎられようと
ﾔﾂはああして笑ってますよ｡
We could cut off an arm or leg,
and he would keep on smiling like that.
う～ん 痛みでﾔﾂを追い詰めるのは
ﾑﾘということか｡
So it's impossible to pressure
him through pain.
しかし どうしたもんかね ﾄｼ｡
Still, what do we do, Toshi?
取り調べは ただ攻め立てれば
いいってもんじゃねえ｡
There's more to an interrogation
than going on the attack.
ｱﾒとﾑﾁを使い分けて
ﾔﾂに取り入り 心の隙を作るんだ｡
We'll use the "carrot and stick"
technique to make him talk.
情報を吐かそうなんて考えるな｡
Lose the mindset of forcing
information from him.
こちらから近づき
かすめとるんだ｡
We're going to get close
to him and snatch it.
So you want to win him over...
取り入るって あんな変態殺人鬼｡
How exactly are we supposed to
get a serial killer to warm up?
どうやったら
お近づきになれるんですか？
If someone like him had been in my class, I
wouldn't have wanted to be friends with him.
あんなﾔﾂ ｸﾗｽが同じでも
友達になれるﾀｲﾌﾟじゃないですよ｡
卒業までひと言も
会話交わさないﾚﾍﾞﾙですよ｡
I would have graduated without
saying a word to him.
大丈夫だ｡ 卒業前はｲﾔなﾔﾂほど
いいﾔﾂに見えるもんだ｡
It's fine.
When you're about to graduate, the people
you couldn't stand all look like nice people.
いや なにが大丈夫なんですか？
何を卒業するんですか？
Uh, how is it fine?
What are we graduating from?
土方さん ﾁｬﾝｽですよ 友達作る｡
Hijikata-san, this is your chance
to make a friend.
３年間 机に突っ伏したまま
学園生活終えるつもりですかい？
Do you intend to end three years of school
without ever lifting your head off your desk?
Don't talk about me like I'm
some sorry, lonely guy!
人を寂しいﾔﾂみたいに言うな！
You'll never make any friends if you
aren't willing to approach anyone.
自分から話しかけないと
友達なんてできませんよ｡
身体測定とか みんなのﾃﾝｼｮﾝ
上がってるときが狙い目なんです｡
Physical exams are a great time
to try, with everybody hyped up.
あれ？ お前もﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ派？ みたいな
あのﾉﾘでいってみなさいよ｡
"Oh? You wear briefs?"
You know, something along those lines.
誰がﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ派だ！
Who are you accusing
of wearing briefs?!
Go for it!
がんばって｡ 勇気を出して ﾄｼ！
Be brave, Toshi!
心の扉を｡ ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌの扉を開いて ﾄｼ！
Open his heart!
Open his briefs, Toshi!
おい なにﾃﾒｴら 面倒ごと
人に押し付けようとしてんだ｡
Hey! Why are you trying to
push the dirty work on me?!
山崎 お前いけ｡
え？
Yamazaki, you go.
お前ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ派だろ いけ｡
You wear briefs, right?
Get going.
No, I wear boxers!
いや ｵﾚ ﾄﾗﾝｸｽ派なんですけど｡
Shut up.
うるせえ｡
ほとんどﾌﾞﾘｰﾌみたいなもんだろ｡
You might as well be wearing briefs.
存在そのものが
なんかﾓｯｻﾘしてるだろ｡
You ooze lameness...
No, wait...
いや… ちょっと そもそも
向こうもﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ派かどうかも…｡
We don't even know if he wears briefs...
あ～ん ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞ ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞと｡
いいんだよっ！
ちょっと…｡
Stop wasting time and get going!
ああっ！
Open!
開いて｡ ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌの扉を開いて ｻﾞｷ｡
Open his briefs, Zaki!
Ow-ow-ow...
ｲﾃﾃ｡
S-Scary!
《怖え！》
This guy's really creepy up close!
《近くで見たら
ﾒﾁｬﾒﾁｬ不気味だよ ｺｲﾂ｡
Like he's going to jump me at any time!
今にも
飛びかかってきそうなんだけど》
ｻﾞｷ ｱﾒとﾑﾁだぞ｡
Zaki, carrot and stick.
ときに厳しく攻め
ときに優しく言葉をかける｡
Mercilessly pressure him, while offering
gentle words of comfort.
ﾂﾝﾃﾞﾚの原理を巧みに利用し
ﾔﾂの心を掌握するんだ｡
[Note: A character archetype, where a rough person suddenly becomes sweet, under certain circumstance.]
Use the tsundere principle
to catch his heart!
《落ち着け｡ 相手は
手足が拘束されて動けないんだ｡
Calm down.
His arms and legs are chained
together so he can't move.
後ろのﾏｼﾞｯｸﾐﾗｰで
みんなも見ててくれるし➡
And everybody's watching me through
the two-way mirror behind me.
まずは 一発かましたれ｡
I'll start with a threat.
ﾔﾂは完全に
ｵﾚたち警察をﾅﾒきっている｡
He's looking down on the police.
あの余裕の笑顔を
引き剥がさんことには➡
I won't be able to accomplish anything if
I can't get that smug smile off his face!
なにをやってもﾑﾀﾞだ》
つぎはぎﾊｹﾞ ｺﾗｧ！
Fuck it, patchwork baldy!
ﾃﾒｴは いつまでﾉﾗﾘｸﾗﾘ
しらばっくれてるつもりだ！
How long you gonna keep playin' it cool?
警察ﾅﾒるのも たいがいにしろよ｡
このｸｿｯﾀﾚが！
Don't mess with the police, mothafucka!
こっちもﾋﾏじゃねえんだよ｡
ｱﾆﾒも４年目で原作ｽﾄｯｸ完全ｾﾞﾛ！
We don't have all day here!
The anime's on its fourth year, with our
stock of original material running out!
毎週 原稿ﾌｧｯｸｽで
送ってもらってる状態だぞ！
We get manga manuscripts
faxed over every week!
余裕ねえんだよ！
We're on the ropes!
Everybody's stressed out to the limit!
みんなｽﾄﾚｽ抱えて
いっぱいいっぱい｡
We don't got time to waste on
a guest character like you!
ﾃﾒｴらﾎﾟｯと出のｹﾞｽﾄｷｬﾗ相手してる
ところじゃねえんだよ！
So cut to the chase and spill your guts!
わかったら ﾓﾀﾓﾀしくさってねえで
さっさと全部吐け！
なんの話をしてるんだ ｱｲﾂは？
What's he talking about?
I wanna play DQ too!
[Note: Refers to the recently released "Dragon Quest IX".]
(山崎)ｵﾚだってさ
ﾎﾝﾄはﾄﾞﾗｸｴやりてえよ｡
I haven't beaten it yet!
まだｸﾘｱできてねえんだよ｡
全部ｶﾞﾏﾝして仕事してんの｡
But I'm sucking it up and
working my ass off!
やりたいことほっぽっといて
お前みたいなﾔﾂ相手してんの｡
I have to deal with people like you
instead of doing what I want to do!
おい なんか だんだん
ただの愚痴になってねえ？
Hey, isn't he just bitching now?
Damn it!
ﾁｸｼｮｳ！ ｵﾚも
｢こち亀｣の秋本先生のように➡
Why can't I get a job like the one
Kochikame's Akimoto has?!
[Note: Osamu Akimoto is the manga artist of "Kochikame (Kochira Katsushika-ku Kameari Koen Mae Hashutsujo)," a very popular police manga/anime.]
早く仕事ができればな！
ねぇ 何してんの ｱｲﾂ｡
What is he doing?
もう全然 犯人に
向かってないんだけど｡
He's not even looking at the suspect.
原作者の心情を
熱く語ってるだけなんだけど｡
He's just channeling the author
of this manga now.
『微熱大陸』観ました！
[Note: Binetsu Tairiku is a parody of the Japanese TV show "Jyonetsu Tairiku."]
I watched Binetsu Tairiku!
観たあと めっちゃ
仕事できそうな気がして➡
I was all pumped up to
work after watching it,
机に向かったけど
やっぱ全然ﾀﾞﾒだった！
so I sat down at my desk,
but it was no good!
ｵﾚは あなたのようには
なれません！
I can't be like you! I'm worthless!
ﾀﾞﾒ人間です～！
いや 知らねえから｡
いいかげんにしろよ｡
Yeah, we don't care.
Cut it out.
ここは 空知の
ざんげ室じゃねえんだよ｡
[Note: Hideaki Sorachi= original
manga author for Gintama.]
This isn't a place for Sorachi to repent.
どうせ ｵﾚなんて
どうせ ｵﾚなんて…｡
I'm just... I'm just...
♪♪(田中)
｢ﾃﾚﾚ～ﾚ ﾃﾚﾚ～ﾚ～ﾚ ﾚ～ﾚﾚﾚ｣
これは
『微熱大陸』のﾃｰﾏ曲的な…｡
This is the theme from Binetsu Tairiku...
あの太郎的な…｡ お前…｡
The Taro song...
You...
確かに あなたは とんだﾀﾞﾒ人間だ｡
You are certainly a failure of a human.
なに!? お前に言われたくないな！
What?
Like you're one to talk.
仕事が遅いことがじゃありません｡
I'm not referring to your
tardy work habits.
山の頂を仰ぎ見て
卑屈になっていることが… です｡
I'm talking about how you gaze at the
top of the mountain in servitude.
かがめばかがむほど
山頂は遠くなりますよ｡
The path to the top will only grow
longer if you belittle yourself.
頂は おのれの卑小さを
知るために➡
A mountain peak does not exist
to show how small you are.
そびえ立っているのでは
ありません｡
ただ目指すために あるのです｡
It's there to provide you with a goal.
山道で
かがんでいるﾋﾏがあったら➡
If you have to wander down a side path,
ゆっくりでもいい
登っていきなさい｡
you should take your time
to slowly climb up.
秋本山は
30年かけてできた山です｡
The mountain you call Akimoto-san
was the product of thirty years.
[Note: Tanaka is using a mountain metaphor to describe the Kochikame manga artist. "Kochikame" has been in Weekly Shonen Jump since 1976. ]
そうたやすくは登れません｡
It won't be an easy climb for you.
あなたも 30年かけて
登るつもりでいきなさい｡
You must be prepared
to spend thirty years.
Step by step, as steady as a turtle...
[Note: Part of the manga title "Kochikame"
is "kame", which is turtle.]
一歩ずつ
ｶﾒのように 確かな足取りで｡
それでも 頂には
たどり着けないかもしれない｡
It's possible that you'll
never reach the top.
途中で
力尽きてしまうかもしれない｡
You may burn out halfway.
だけど
そこから見える景色はきっと➡
However, you'll still have a better
view than you do now.
今よりﾏｼなものに
なっているはずですよ｡
ありがとうございました｡
失礼します｡
Thank you very much.
If you'll excuse me.
お前 何しにいったんだ！
What did you go in there for?!
なんで お前が
ｱﾒに足からめとられてんだよ！
Why did you fall for his carrot?!
なんで ﾃﾒｴに ﾑﾁ打ってんだよ！
Why did you let him use
the stick on you?!
ｵﾒｴが いろいろ吐いて
どうすんだよ！
Why were you the one
who spilled his guts?!
犯人に吐かせんだよ！
You're supposed to get the
suspect to spill his guts!
いや… でも
お近づきになれました｡
Still, I was able to get close to him.
ＤＶＤ 焼いてもらいました｡
『微熱大陸』｡
He burned me a DVD of Binetsu Tairiku.
完全に お前が
取り入られてんだろ！
He's the one who won you over!
あっ 山崎
ｵﾚにも貸してくれい｡
Hey, Yamazaki.
Lend me that.
これで いつも優しい秋本先生が
取材陣に➡
Now, I'll always be able
to see the rare scene,
where the interviewers ask kind Mr. Akimoto
what he's most angry about right now,
[Note: Refers to the documentary Jyonetsu Tairiku (Passionate Continent - Documentary). Osamu Akimoto was featured in February 2009.]
｢今いちばん怒ってることは
何ですか？｣って聞かれて➡
｢取材が長いこと｣って答えた
ﾚｱｶｯﾄが また観られる！
and he gives his long answer in the interview.
ｵﾒｴは どんな楽しみ方してんだ！
How could you enjoy that?!
あの秋本先生が
ああ言うってことは➡
It must have been a really long interview
to make Mr. Akimoto say that.
よっぽど
長い取材だったんだよ！
最後の取材陣を取材し返す➡
Rewatch the part where he's
interviewing the interviewers!
あくなき探究心のほうを
ﾘﾋﾟｰﾄしてみろ！
山崎 お前は
ﾔﾂに おちょくられたんだよ｡
Yamazaki, you let him
pull a fast one on you.
あんな殺人鬼に
説法なんざ説かれて➡
I can't believe you let yourself
be lectured by that murderer.
まるめこまれやがって｡
情けねえ…｡
Pathetic...
やはり 一筋縄でいくﾔﾂでは
ないようだな｡
He'll be a tough nut to crack.
よし 次は ｵﾚがいこう｡
Okay. I'll go next.
攻めるのは もう十分なはず｡
That's enough threatening.
ｵﾚは ｱﾒでいく｡
｢はぐれ刑事｣ よろしく｡
I'll go with carrot.
Just like the rogue detective.
[Note: Parody of the police TV drama "Hagure Keiji
Jyunjyo-ha (Rogue Detective Naïve Type).]
Detective Gorilla: Empathy Type.
情をもってして
ﾔﾂを説き伏せてみせる｡
I'll use empathy to sway him over.
(土方)つ～か ごりら刑事って
ごりらになってんだけど｡
It says Detective Gorilla. You're a gorilla.
人から はぐれてんだけど｡
You've strayed from the human race.
課長 ｵﾚに何かあったら
娘たちのことを… 頼む｡
Chief, take care of my daughters
if anything happens to me.
(土方)
どこに課長と娘がいるんだ？
Where's the chief or your daughters?
ｹｲﾝ刑事 お前は
ｱｸｼｮﾝ勉強する前に➡
Detective Kane.
[Note: Parody of Kane Kosugi, the son of martial art star Sho Kosugi. He appeared in many physical challenge shows.]
You should learn to act
before you learn action.
芝居を勉強しろ｡
Yeah, whatever happened
to Detective Kane?
(沖田)ﾎﾝﾄに今
どこにいるんだ？ ｹｲﾝ刑事…｡
ﾑｼｮのくさいﾒｼは飽きただろう｡
今日は特別だ｡
You're probably sick of the prison slop.
I've brought you something
special today.
好きなだけ食べなさい｡
ごりさん特製ｶﾂ丼だ｡
Eat as much as you want.
It's Gorilla's special katsudon.
[Note: Katsudon (Fried pork cutlet and egg on rice) is often used in Japanese police TV dramas as a prop to convince hungry suspects.]
ｶﾂ丼ってｱｲﾃﾑは人情派ですけど➡
The katsudon might be
considered empathetic,
食わせてる画が とても
人情派に見えないんですけど｡
but the way he's feeding
it to him is anything but.
Eat up.
非人情派にしか
見えないんですけど…｡
The exact opposite, in fact.
よっこいしょ…｡
All right now...
実はな… 私にも➡
Fact is, I have a son your age.
ちょうど お前さんと
同じくらいの息子がいてな｡
(土方)おい ごりら刑事！
いったい何歳の設定だよ！
Hey, Detective Gorilla!
How old are you supposed to be?!
息子 ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬおっさんだぞ｡
That makes your son an old man!
お前さんを見てると
ｱｲﾂを思い出す｡
You remind me of my son.
今 どこで
何をやってるんだか…｡
I wonder where he is now...
ｱﾒﾘｶで ｱｸｼｮﾝを勉強するとか
のたまっていたが…｡
He said something about studying
action in America...
(土方)なんで ｹｲﾝ刑事
息子の設定になってんだよ！
How did Detective Kane
become your son?!
あれも 一時は ｸﾞﾚてねぇ｡
There was a period when he
went down the wrong path...
夜な夜な やれ ｢筋肉番付｣だ
やれ ｢SASUKE｣だって➡
He'd be immersed in dangerous
bodybuilding shows every night
[Note: Kinniku Banzuke (Muscle ranking) and SASUKE are names of physical challenge shows in Japan.]
危険なﾏｯｽﾙ地帯にばかり
繰り出してねぇ｡
like Muscle Ranking and SASUKE...
(土方)いや 確かに危険だけども！
Yeah, that sure is dangerous, but...
Murofushi, Shoei...
[Note: Koji Murofushi is a Japanese gold medalist hammer thrower who appeared in the 2004 Olympics. Shoei is a Japanese actor who competed on Sasuke in early 2000s.]
(近藤)室伏 照英 どこの馬の
ﾏｯｽﾙとも知れんﾔﾂらとつるみ➡
Those were the nameless muscle
freaks he joined with,
ﾏｯｽﾙを吸ったり
盗んだﾏｯｽﾙで走り出したり➡
as they snorted muscles,
and raced around in stolen muscles.
[Note: Kondo is using "muscle" in
lieu of "drug" and "motorcycle".]
それは ひどかった…｡
It was awful...
What the hell are stolen muscles?!
(土方)盗んだﾏｯｽﾙって何だよ！
どんな状態？
How would that work?!
(近藤)そんな折 妻が
ﾏｯｽﾙをﾏｽらって倒れてな…｡
Eventually, my wife collapsed
because of her muscles.
(土方)おい！
もう意味わかんねえよ！
What?!
You're not even making any sense now!
もういい！
ｹｲﾝ刑事のことは もういい！
Enough! Enough about Detective Kane!
(近藤)息子のﾏｯｽﾙっぷりに
心労が たたったんだろう…｡
She must have been worried
about our son's muscles...
(土方)だから ﾏｯｽﾙから
離れろっつ～んだよ！
Stop talking about muscles!
(近藤)だが
母が危篤状態だというのに➡
But our son never came to the hospital,
despite his mother's condition.
息子は ついに
病院に来ることはなかった｡
ﾔﾂは ﾑｼｮに
ぶち込まれていたんだ｡
He had been locked up in the slammer!
(土方)おい！ なに ｹｲﾝ勝手に
前科持ちにしてんだ!?
Hey!
Why are you giving Kane
a criminal record?!
(近藤)ﾏｯｽﾙ不法所持｡
Illegal possession of muscles.
ﾔﾂは 自室のﾀﾝｽの中で
密かに 池谷を栽培していたんだ｡
He'd been secretly growing
Iketani in his closet.
[Note: Kondo is using Muscle to refer to drugs here. Yukio Iketani is a gymnast and Olympic medalist.]
(土方)だから どんな状態だ!?
How would that even work?!
He might have avoided arrest if
it had been the younger Iketani,
(近藤)池谷弟なら
ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘ 執行猶予もついたが➡
[Note: The Iketani brothers. Yukio Iketani and his younger brother, Naoki Iketani are both gymnasts.]
but the older Iketani assures
you of a sentencing.
池谷兄なら 実刑は免れん｡
(土方)何の違い!?
What's the difference?
I was enraged, despondent...
(近藤)私は怒り 失望し
ﾔﾂと絶縁しようとした｡
I considered cutting ties with him.
親の死に目に あろうことか
ﾏｯｽﾙ中毒で会えぬﾔﾂを➡
How could I call him my son when
he hadn't come to see his mother
どうして息子なんて呼べる？
on her deathbed because
of his muscle addiction!
だが そんな私に
おそらく いちばん失望し➡
But as I sat there in despair
and regret, my wife told me.
無念であろう妻が 言ったんだ｡
｢逃げないで｣と…｡
Don't run away.
子供が いいことをしたとき➡
If it's the duty of a parent to praise a child
and rejoice when he does something right,
世界で 最も喜び
褒めてやるのが 親の責務ならば➡
子供が 罪を犯したとき➡
it's also the duty of a parent to curse and
mourn when he does something wrong!
世界で 最も悲しみ
憎んでやるのも➡
親の責務なんだと｡
息子が出所したとき➡
Once my son was released, I beat him
to a pulp... Till he almost died...
私は 息子を
力いっぱい殴りつけた 死ぬほど｡
だが ﾔﾂが更生し
一人立ちしたとき➡
However, when he repented his
old ways and stood up,
私は 力いっぱい
息子を抱きしめた… 死ぬほど｡
I embraced him as tight as I
could... Till he almost died...
子供が どんなになろうと➡
It's the job of a parent to accept their
child, no matter what they become.
それを受け止めてやるのが
親というものだ｡
だが 子供を憎みたい親が
どこにいる｡
However, no parent would
want to hate their child.
子を憎み 愛すのが親の責務なら➡
If it's the parent's responsibility
to love and hate their child,
子供の責務とは 何だ？
what is the child's responsibility?
月並みなことを
言わせてもらう｡
I'll make this simple.
Don't make your parents suffer.
これ以上 親御さんを
苦しめるな｡
どうか 私の妻のような思いは
させんでやってくれ｡
Please don't make them go
through what my wife did.
You have committed many sins.
お前さんは
たくさんの罪を犯した｡
It's too late for you to erase them.
今さら あがなえるものではない｡
Your parents will have to bear that
burden for the rest of their lives.
お前の親御さんも
これから一生➡
それを背負っていくことに
なるだろう｡
だが まだ 今なら
背負わずに済む罪もあるはずだ｡
But there are still sins that
you can make up for.
今なら 親御さんを苦しめる荷を➡
It's still possible for you to lessen
the burden on your parents!
ひとつ 取り払う方法が
あるはずだ｡
吐きます｡
I'll spill...
(近藤)えっ!?
I'll spill everything...
吐きます… 洗いざらい すべて｡
(近藤)ｱﾝﾀ！
ま まさか…➡
You...
D-Don't tell me he actually
convinced that murderer?!
あの殺人鬼が
あんな説得に応じるのか!?
《見たか ﾄｼ！ 総悟！
Did you see that, Toshi?! Sogo?!
It's all about heart!
ﾊｰﾄなんだ！ ｵﾚのﾊｰﾄを
ぶち込んだｱﾒこそが➡
My heartfelt carrot was able to
soften this hardened criminal!
どんな がんじがらめになった
犯人の心情をも解き放って…》
おぼろしゃ～！
(土方)別のものを吐いた～！
Touch this killer deep down...
He spilled something else!
♪♪～
なんじゃこりゃ～！
What the hell is this?!
[Note: Spoof of Police drama TV series "Taiyo ni hoero! (Howl to the sun!)" from the 70-80's. G-pan(Jeans pants) detective played by Yusaku Matsuda died in the series using this line.]
Why did this turn into a Detective
G-Pan death scene?!
(土方)なんで ｼﾞｰﾊﾟﾝﾃﾞｶ殉職
みたいになってんだよ！
｢はぐれ刑事｣じゃなかったのか？
Weren't you a rogue detective?!
なんで ｹﾞﾛかけられて
『太陽にほえろ』的な➡
Why are they playing the death music from Howl
to the Sun for a scene where he got barfed on?!
殉職のﾃｰﾏが流れてんだよ！
Ah, I'm sorry.
あの すみません
これ ｶﾂ丼 腐ってませんか？
I believe this katsudon is spoiled?
H-Hold on...
ま 待ってくれよ｡
こりゃ まだ 腐ってねえよ｡
It hasn't spoiled yet.
待ってくれ 捨てないでくれ｡
Please wait...
Don't throw this away...
こりゃ まだ 三日前のなんだ｡
It's only three days old!
あとから食おうと思って
とっといたんだ！
I was saving it to eat later!
(土方)いや 腐ってんだろう
ｶﾂ丼も ｱﾝﾀの頭も｡
No, the katsudon's definitely spoiled.
So is your head, for that matter.
Forgive me.
すみません せっかく私のために
用意してくれたのに➡
After you went through the trouble
to prepare that for me, well...
あの 責任とって
全部食べますから➡
I'll take responsibility
by eating all of it,
そこ 置いといてください｡
so please leave it here.
What the hell is this?!
なんじゃそりゃ～！
Wait... Please wait!
ま 待ってくれ！
持ってかないでくれ！
Don't take this from me!
ﾑﾘしないでくれ！
Don't overdo it!
ｵﾚは 人殺しには
なりたくねえんだよ！
I don't want to become a killer!
Hey, could you drop the
crappy imitation?
(土方)おい！ いちいち
中途半端なﾓﾉﾏﾈすんじゃねえよ！
Please set your mind at ease.
安心してください｡
あなたは 悪くありません｡
You've done nothing wrong.
I have faith in you.
私は あなたを信じます｡
If it's the parent's duty to
bear the child's sins,
子の罪を罰し ともに苦しむのが
親の役目なら➡
無実を信じ ともに戦う役目は
友が担いましょう｡
the "friend" should take the duty of having
faith and fighting by your side.
うわぁ～っ！
Gorilla-san!
ごりさん！
ｼﾞｰﾊﾟﾝじゃねえのかよ!?
Weren't you going for G-Pan?!
What happened to the rogue detective?!
つうか はぐれ刑事
どこ行ったんだよ!?
Gori-san! Hang in there!
ごりさん しっかりしろ！ おい！
Hey!
や… やられたよ… ｵﾚの完敗だ｡
He got me...
I was soundly defeated...
After I suspected him and
fed him this pig feed...
罪を疑ったうえ こんな
ﾌﾞﾀのｴｻを食わしたｵﾚを…➡
友と… ｵﾚを信じると…｡
He called me friend... He
still believed in me...
Yeah, why a pork cutlet?
(土方)だから なんでｶﾂなんだよ！
Shouldn't that be a cigarette?!
普通 ﾀﾊﾞｺだろ ﾀﾊﾞｺ！
ﾏﾖﾗﾃﾞｶ ドＳﾃﾞｶ… あとは…｡
Detective Mayora...
[Note: Spoof of Police drama TV series "Taiyo Ni Hoero! (Howl to the sun!)". Each detective was given a nickname for the way they dress and their personality.]
Detective Sadist...
The rest is up to you...
ごりさ～ん！
Gori-san!
(土方)どうなってやがんだ!?
What's going on?
Our attempt to convince that murderer
説き伏せてるつもりが 逆に
説き伏せられていく…➡
is backfiring...
あんな殺人鬼に…｡
土方さん｡ どうやら
あっちのほうが➡
Hijikata-san...
He seems to be much better than
us at using carrot and stick.
ｵﾚたちより よっぽど
ｱﾒとﾑﾁの使い方が 上手いらしい｡
[?-kun]
土方さんの言う ｱﾒとﾑﾁとは➡
Your concept of carrot and stick
[?-chan, you're too close!]
単純に言ってしまえば
ﾑﾁで ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝぶっ叩いてくる➡
is basically where someone who's
always beating you from behind
[It's embarrassing when people are watching]
[What~ That's not true~]
恐ろしい
ﾔﾂが➡
[On the other hand]
[Geez, I can't believe you, stupid ?-kun]
says something kind or righteous,
ふと 優しい言葉をかけてきたり➡
正義っぽいことをすると➡
[Sorry, XX-chan...]
you appreciate it more than if it
came from someone normal.
普通のﾔﾂの言動より
美しく感じるっつう➡
いわば ｷﾞｬｯﾌﾟﾙｰﾙのこと｡
[I love you, ?-kun]
What you might call the gap principle.
(土方)何この
(沖田)
頭の悪い図式｡
しかし…｡
What's with the really dumb visual aids?
[...is more of a turn-on]
However...
(土方)は？
まだ続けんのかよ この図式｡
What? We're not done with
these weird visuals?
(沖田)ﾔﾂの場合
凶悪な殺人鬼という➡
He's already known to be a vicious killer,
肩書きを持っている時点で➡
so you could say that we've already
experienced his stick.
ｵﾚたちは すでにﾔﾂのﾑﾁで
打たれてるもんなんでさぁ｡
By the time we try to give him the stick,
ｵﾚたちがﾔﾂに
さぁﾑﾁ打つぞというときは➡
もう とっくにﾔﾂは
ﾑﾁを打ち終わってるんでさぁね｡
he's already finished.
[Mr. Akimoto is wonderful...!!!]
あとは
聞こえのいいｾﾘﾌを吐くだけで➡
He just has to spew some
nice-sounding crap,
[Oh... My friend...]
ｱﾒとﾑﾁの図式が出来上がる｡
to accomplish the carrot and stick effect.
We will always be behind in the score,
ｵﾚたちは
どうしても ﾔﾂより数手遅れて➡
このような結果に
なってしまうわけです｡
which is why we aren't
getting any results.
ｸｯ…｡
ｵﾚたちが勝つには➡
If we want to win, we have to achieve
carrot and stick before he does.
ﾔﾂより早く こちらがｱﾒとﾑﾁを
ﾔﾂに叩き込むこと｡
そんなことができるのか？
Can we do that?
ﾌｯ １人ではﾑﾘでさぁ｡ でも…｡
It's impossible to do it alone.
But...
そうか！
I see!
おら～っ！
なに まったりこいてんだ！
こっから拷問の時間の始まりだ！
Don't make yourself too comfortable!
Your torture's about to start!
《土方:上司の命を狙う
超ド級のＳ！
A top-class sadist who's aiming
for his superior's life!
And...
そして！》
大丈夫ですか？
おｹｶﾞはありませんか？
Are you okay?!
Are you hurt?!
《沖田:上司にも部下にも
問題児を抱える➡
The follow-up master who cleans up after
superiors and subordinates alike!
ﾌｫﾛｰの達人！》
《２人:２人で協力すれば 一瞬で
極上のｱﾒとﾑﾁが出来上がる》
If the two of us work together,
we can form the best carrot and stick!
《これで…》
Now...
《終わりだ！》
It's over.
あの～ すみません
何やってるんですか？
Uh, sorry...
What are you doing?
《２人:な… なに!?》
Wh-What?!
《ｱﾒとﾑﾁが効かない！ ﾊﾞｶな…》
Carrot and stick isn't working!
Impossible!
《今のは完全にｸﾘｰﾝﾋｯﾄしたはず》
That should have been a clean hit!
大丈夫ですか？
座って お話しましょう｡
Are you okay?
Why don't you have a
seat so we can talk?
I was feeling lonely because
everybody had gone.
みなさんが
いなくなってしまって➡
ちょうど
寂しいと思ってたとこなんです｡
(２人)うわっ！ ｸｯ…｡
A murderer feeling lonely...?!
《殺人鬼が寂しいだと!?》
This guy has brought out
a real carrot bomb!
《ｺｲﾂ… この期に及んで➡
超ド級のｱﾒ玉を
投げつけてきやがった！》
(２人)これは耐えきれない！
We can't hold him off!
土方さん どうやらｵﾚたちは➡
Hijikata-san!
We've had this completely
wrong from the beginning!
最初から とんでもない勘違いを
していたようでさぁ！
思い出してくだせえ｡
Think back!
ｺｲﾂの性癖は ドＭ｡
This guy is a masochist!
つまり 通常のｱﾒとﾑﾁは
ｺｲﾂには通用しない！
Which means a normal carrot
and stick won't work on him!
そ… そうか！
I-I see!
A masochist won't feel any
pain from the stick!
ドＭにとっては
ﾑﾁは なんら苦痛に値しない｡
つまり ｺｲﾂにとってのｱﾒとは
ﾑﾁのこと！
So his carrot would be the stick!
《順序が逆だった！
We had the order wrong!
ｺｲﾂは今までｵﾚたちがやってきた➡
Using the stick and then carrot in that
order didn't have any effect on him!
ﾑﾁ ｱﾒの順序じゃ
何の意味も持たねえ！
ｺｲﾂは ｱﾒ ﾑﾁの順序で
叩き込まなければ➡
We have to hit him with
the carrot, then the stick!
何も効果はない》
《いや 待て…｡
No, wait...
さっきのｵﾚのｱﾒなら
効果は まだ持続しているはず｡
My carrot shouldn't have
lost its effect yet.
つまり あと一撃｡
あと一撃 ﾑﾁを叩き込めば➡
Which means we need one more...
One more lash with the stick to
complete our carrot and stick!
ｱﾒとﾑﾁは完成する！
だが遠い｡
戦意がなくなっていく…｡
But he's so far away...
I'm losing my will to fight...
ﾀﾞﾒだ… もうｵﾚは… 戦えねえ》
It's no use...
I can no longer...
fight...
(近藤)ﾄｼ！ ﾄｼ！ ﾄｼ！
Toshi.
Toshi...
Toshi!
(近藤)ﾄｼｰｯ!!
Vice-Chief!
副長！
お前ら！
You guys!
《土方:力が… 力がわいてくる！
I can...
I can feel power surging through me!
そうか… ｱﾒとﾑﾁとは➡
I see...
Carrot and stick isn't
limited to the enemy.
なにも 敵に対してのみ
使うものではなかったんだな｡
この窮地こそはﾑﾁ｡
Our plight was the stick.
そして この窮地にあっても
なお立ち上がる仲間たちこそ➡
And the comrades who are able
to rise up out of this plight
ｵﾚたちを奮い立たせる
最高のｱﾒだ！》
serve as the greatest carrot!
(土方たち)いけ～っ！
Go!
あのう
盛り上がってるとこ すみません｡
Uh, this might be a bad
time to interrupt you all.
あのう
手違いがあったらしくてですね➡
Uh, there was a mistake.
その人
田中古兵衛じゃありません｡
That person isn't Kohei Tanaka.
殺人鬼でもありません｡
He's not a killer either.
田中加兵衛っていう➡
He's Kahei Tanaka, a good citizen
who helped catch a shoplifter.
万引き犯 捕まえた
善良な市民らしいです｡
万引き犯 捕まえたとき
ｼｮｰｳｲﾝﾄﾞｰに突っ込んで➡
He crashed into a store window when he
caught the shoplifter, and hurt himself.
体中 ｹｶﾞしたらしいんだけど➡
その補償とかで
奉行所に来てたら➡
so we brought him to the
station to get treatment,
名前似てるから間違えたらしくて｡
but there was a mix-up since
his name was similar.
ほんと すみません｡
今 本物の古兵衛 連れてくるんで｡
I'm really sorry about this.
I'll bring the real Kohei now.
ｱﾒとﾑﾁが…｡
ｶﾂ丼はくさりかけが…｡
Combine the carrot with the stick...
My katsudon is starting to spoil...
Mr. Akimoto works so hard...
He was just a smiling nice person...
What the hell is this?!
(土方たち)なんじゃこりゃ～っ!!
[Preview]
Uh, Eli, was that how you always looked?
Was that how you always were?
The next episode...
"It's What's On The Inside That Counts."
Plus another one.
[Preview]
["It's What's On The Inside That Counts,
But Only To A Certain Extent."]
[Two parts starring the GinTama mascots,
Elizabeth and Sadaharu.]
[Why are the titles similar? You'll find out next week.]
[See you next time.]